ANA MARJANOVIC

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ana-marjanovic-67089522 https://github.com/marjanana

Summary

Web development specialist with experience in managing and designing high profile websites demonstrating expertise in responsive design, rendering, and problem solving to provide exceptional user support and user experience.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, Knockout.js (MVVM), Bootstrap, Jasmine, Grunt.

Other: Git/GitHub, Adobe Indesign, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Project Experience

Neighborhood Map http://marjanana.github.io/P5-1-Neighborhood-Map/

March 2016

- Created a single-page, responsive application built with Knockout.js framework and hosted on GitHub Pages.
- Developed a full-page map that loads with 5 popular boxing gyms in New York City.
- Integrated recent pictures taken at each location (retrieved by AJAX request).

Website Optimization http://marjanana.github.io/frontend-nanodegree-mobile-portfolio-master/ January 2016

- Optimized critical rendering path of existing website to achieve PageSpeed Insights score above 90.
- Coded player, enemies, and other game entities in JavaScript's object-oriented pseudo-classical style.
- Eliminated inefficiencies in the website's scroll animation (site now scrolls at 60 frames per second).

Arcade Game Clone http://marjanana.github.io/frontend-nanodegree-arcade-game/

November 2015

- Cloned the classic game, Frogger and used the art assets and game engine provided by Udacity.
- Coded player, enemies, and other game entities in JavaScript's object-oriented pseudo-classical style.
- Created enemy subclasses with different movement patterns.

Work Experience

Electronic Design and Multimedia (EDM), CCNY

Teaching Assistant

January 2010 - Present

- Work with EDM majors enrolled in the Senior Thesis Class at a public college.
- Edit thesis briefs, tutor students in creating final thesis statements, and critique student project presentations.
- Help with set-up for the EDM Senior Thesis Class exhibition installation.
- Write wall text for the EDM Senior Thesis Class exhibition.

The Writing Center, CCNY

Writing Tutor February 2014 - Present

- Provide one-on-one assistance for students working on writing assignments and projects from any discipline.
- Collaborate with a four-person team in planning and executing monthly professional development sessions.

Education

Udacity: Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

The City College of New York: M.A., Art History/Museum Studies, GPA: 3.81

Belgrade University, Faculty of Philosophy: B.A., Art History

October 2005

Activities

Art Observed: Blogger.

Summer 2011

Amateur Boxer

2012 - Present